If you just got a Ninja Creamy, let me
get you started with all the essentials
you need to start making the best
possible recipes. First things first, go
ahead and order some more pints. You're
going to need more than the two it comes
with, or some of them even come with
one. If you want to plan for the week
and meal prep the Ninja Creamy, you need
more than one container. It's really a
matter of how much freezer space you
have. I would say at minimum get two,
but if you have the space, get at least
four. Starting with the base, I like to
use high protein milk in most my
recipes. This is Fair Life. It's fat-
free, a little higher protein than
normal skim milk, but you can easily
substitute with any fat-ree or skim
milk. Sometimes I like to use a pre-made
protein shake as well. These are three
of my favorite brands at the moment. And
then obviously you need some cottage
cheese. Guys, if you think I'm putting
cottage cheese in my ice cream, you are
crazy. This stays far away from the
creamy. But Eli, how am I going to
measure all these recipes? You need a
scale. You need a kitchen scale. This
one goes down to the 0.1 g, which is
what I recommend. A lot of scales just
go to the full gram and they're just
more inaccurate, especially when you're
measuring powders and small ingredients.
Now, if you've ever had ice cream, it's
pretty sweet, right? And you're not
going to get that from just milk. So, I
like to add sweetener. These are some of
my favorites. This is the one I've used
for years, probably five plus years. And
this one I found on Tik Tok shop. It was
super cheap, so I'm trying it out. Of
course, you can also use sugar. Now,
staying on the topic of the base, you're
going to need a binding agent or
stabilizer. These are the two I
recommend the most. I always use Zantham
gum. A lot of people say they prefer the
guar gum and some people use jello
pudding mix. I'm not a huge fan of the
jello pudding mix. I think it tastes
more like a frozen pudding than ice
cream. And one more thing for bases are
extracts. I always use vanilla bean
paste, vanilla extract, have a cookie
butter extract, a cake batter extract,
peppermint extract. I would recommend
starting off vanilla bean paste or
extract, cake batter extract, and a
peppermint extract if you want to make
some mint flavors, especially now that
we're in the winter time. And last but
not least, you can't forget about the
mix-ins. That's honestly my favorite
part about the Ninja Creamy, the fact
that you can add mix-ins. It does the
mixing in for you. Because in my
opinion, every ice cream is better with
something crunchy or chewy or just some
textural difference. These are some of
my favorites. Alpha Prime bites. These
are protein brownies. They have a ton of
flavors. This one, the mint chocolate
chip one, really good. Just came out.
These are protein cookie dough bites
from Fuel. They add a bit of protein.
They taste like cookie dough. Can't
really miss there. And then my all-time
favorite mixin, Oreo Thins. For some
reason, they just mix up so perfectly in
the Ninja Creamy. If you're just getting
started, these ingredients are more than
enough to make dozens of recipes. If you
need recipe inspiration or actual
recipes, check out my page. I also have
a recipe book linked in my bio. 165
recipes in there. low calorie, high
protein ice cream.